<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sophie Nottmeyer</title><link>https://sophistecon.github.io/</link><atom:link href="https://sophistecon.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Sophie Nottmeyer</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://sophistecon.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Sophie Nottmeyer</title><link>https://sophistecon.github.io/</link></image><item><title>Informality and the City Size Wage Premium: Evidence from Brazil</title><link>https://sophistecon.github.io/project/informality-and-the-city-size-wage-premium-evidence-from-brazil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 18:24:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sophistecon.github.io/project/informality-and-the-city-size-wage-premium-evidence-from-brazil/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cities in middle and low income countries are rapidly urbanizing, generating
important economic opportunities and challenges. Among the key potential
benefits are higher individual earnings in larger cities. However, informal labor markets
are a prominent feature in these contexts that may alter the scope of agglomeration
benefits. How does informality affect the relationship between wages and city size? Using
Census data for Brazil, I find that higher levels of informality in the local economy
reduce the city size wage premium. This is because formal and informal workers benefit
from density differently according to which type of worker is contributing to it. In
particular, I show that productive benefits of cities seem to be mainly driven by the
presence of formal workers. Agglomeration in terms of informal workers on the other
hand crowds out some of these benefits for formal workers. Thus, informality seems
to play an important role in shaping the benefits from working in larger cities in less
developed countries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uber for Tractors: Digital Tools for Agricultural Mechanization</title><link>https://sophistecon.github.io/publication/my-example-publication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 18:24:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sophistecon.github.io/publication/my-example-publication/</guid><description>&lt;p>Funded by Structural Transformation and Economic Growth Initiative (STEG) - Conceptualization stage, data collection in progress&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Milky Way: Market Structure and Behavior of Informal Traders in the Kenyan Dairy Sector</title><link>https://sophistecon.github.io/publication/milky-way-market-structure-and-behavior-of-informal-traders-in-the-kenyan-dairy-sector/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 18:24:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sophistecon.github.io/publication/milky-way-market-structure-and-behavior-of-informal-traders-in-the-kenyan-dairy-sector/</guid><description>&lt;p>with Guanghong Xu and Martin Nandelenga. F﻿unded by Private Enterprise Development in Low-Income Countries (PEDL) Programme - Currently in the field&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ethnic Diversity and Technology Choice in Manufacturing</title><link>https://sophistecon.github.io/publication/ethnic-diversity-and-technology-choice-in-manufacturing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 18:23:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sophistecon.github.io/publication/ethnic-diversity-and-technology-choice-in-manufacturing/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://sophistecon.github.io/admin/config.yml</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sophistecon.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>